# **Brett Whitson**

bremwhit@ut.utm.edu +1-731-592-1309

Summary

Dedicated, enthusiastic, and professional programmer with over 3 years of experience seeking to contribute my training and acquired skills within a development/analyst role. Effective in problem solving and guiding projects from conception to completion. Quick on the uptake, eager to learn, and comfortable in both collaborative and self-driven work environments.

#### Education

#### The University of Tennessee at Martin

Martin, TN

May 2020

Github: bremwhit

LinkedIn: brett-whitson

Bachelor of Science, Computer Science

Skills

Languages: C++, C#, C, HTML, CSS, Javascript, JQuery, Java, Python3, Haskell, SQL, Bash, Lua

Tools: Git, Visual Studio, Atom, Docker, Emacs, Slack, Trello

Others: Computer Hardware/Software, Networking Fundamentals, MFD

Experience

## The University of Tennessee at Martin

October 26, 2020 - Present

IT Technician III

- Provide assistance to student workers on issues that required elevation.
- Provide maintenance, technical support, and troubleshooting for desktops, laptops, mobile, and other devices.
- Help to resolve technical issues with Local Area Networks.
- Develop and maintain knowledge of university systems and shared this knowledge with clients to promote computer literacy and efficient use of technology as well as a high level of customer service.
- Participate in the effective operation of the IT Help Desk by taking requests, tracking work tickets, maintaining equipment inventories.

## The University of Tennessee at Martin

April 2018 - August 2020

ITS Field Service Technician Assistant, Config/Install, IT Help Desk

- Configured and prepared incoming PC and Mac machines for the staff and faculty of UT Martin. Installed new machines for staff and faculty.
- Provided field support by diagnosing issues and implementing solutions in a timely manner. Provided technical support in person as well as via computer and phone for faculty, staff, and students at the university.
- Assisted in the training of new Help Desk and Field Services student workers on the usage of the ticketing system and other computer software we used.

### William's Sausage

October 2014 - February 2016

Processing Department

Performed various tasks such as pallet jack and industrial blender operation, deboning, and livestock management across multiple positions in the processing department.

#### **Hampton Inn**

September 2011 - September 2013

Front Desk Customer Service Representative

Performed nightly duties such as front desk reservations and check-ins, along with nightly audits of the guest ledger and training of new front desk employees.

## **Projects**

**Financial/Budgeting Application**: Fall 2017 - Pair programmed to create a finance application in C# using MS Access Database to track and manage spending as well as create budget plans.

**Pseudo-Theremin**: Fall 2018 - Worked as part of a team to create a theremin-like musical instrument with Python and Ruby implemented on a Raspberry Pi microcomputer using ultrasonic sensors and the Sonic Pi application.

Bipartite Graph DFS Algorithm: Spring 2019 - Implemented a DFS Bipartite Graph algorithm to determine whether any given graph is bipartite in four different programming paradigms (Imperative/Procedural, Object-Oriented, Functional, Logical/Constraint-based).

**Docker UI**: Fall 2019 - Collaborated with two others to create an intuitive user interface to better manage local Docker containers using Express.js and Electron.

WebDocker: Fall 2019 - Collaborated with two others to create a web solution allowing users to manage virtualized services (Docker containers) via a browser. First Place Undergraduate Presentation, ACM Mid-Southeast Conference.